Anne Morrow Lindbergh Papers, 1892-1993
Sophia Smith Collection
Anne Morrow Lindbergh papers
1892-1993
Lindbergh, Anne Morrow, 1906-2001
682
162 boxes (81 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
Author; Poet; Aviator. Papers consist of correspondence, diaries, writings, photographs, memorabila, scrapbooks, and printed materials. The writings series includes notes, manuscript drafts, galley proofs, published works, correspondence, reviews, clippings, and other materials collected by Anne Morrow Lindbergh, Charles Lindbergh, family members, and editors during the composition of AML's works, especially North to the Orient, Gift from the Sea, Dearly Beloved, Earth Shine, and the five volume collection of her letters and diaries. Files on Gift from the Sea include hundreds of letters from readers, mostly women. These letters provide an interesting look at American attitudes toward life and work in the 1950s. Notable correspondents include her husband Charles A. Lindbergh; mother Elizabeth Cutter Morrow; sisters Elisabeth Morrow Morgan and Constance Morrow Morgan; Margaret "Monte" Millar, Ruth Oliff Thomas, Sue Beck Vaillant, and Lucia Valentine.
Anne Spencer Morrow Lindbergh was born in Englewood, New Jersey on 22 June 1906, the daughter of ambassador and politician Dwight Morrow and author and Smith College president Elizabeth Cutter Morrow. From 1924-1928 Anne studied literature at Smith College, where she graduated in 1928 with a bachelor's degree in English. In May 1929, after a brief courting period, Anne married Charles Augustus Lindbergh (1902-1974). Anne had met Lindbergh in Mexico in 1927, while her father was serving as ambassador. With Charles, she had six children: Charles Augustus, Jr. (1930-1932), Jon (1932-), Land (1937-), Anne (1940-1993), Scott (1942-), and Reeve (1945-).
In March 1932 Anne's first child, Charles, Jr. ("Charlie"), who was twenty months old, was kidnapped from the Lindberghs' home near Hopewell, New Jersey. The press dubbed the kidnapping the "Crime of the Century." In May 1932 after a seventy-two day search, Charles was found dead in a shallow grave only three miles from the Lindbergh estate. In 1936 Bruno Richard Hauptmann, a German immigrant, convicted criminal, and World War I veteran, was executed by the state of New Jersey for the murder of the Lindbergh baby. In December 1936 the Lindbergh's fled America for England to escape harassment by the press and the general public. In April 1939, with war looming in Europe, the Lindberghs returned home to the United States.
In 1934 Anne published her first book, North to the Orient, based on her flights to China and Japan with Charles in 1931. In 1938, she published her second book, The Listen! The Wind, inspired by her visit to Santiago in the Cape Verde Islands, near the coast of Africa. In 1940 she published her most controversial work, Wave of the Future, which critics--in light of Charles' involvement with the America First movement and the Lindberghs' visits to Germany to meet with high-ranking Nazi officials--considered pro-fascist. Despite such criticism, Anne kept writing, publishing the novel The Steep Ascent in 1944, a thinly-veiled fictitious account of a woman aviator flying with her husband over Europe. In 1955 Anne published her classic work and bestseller Gift from the Sea, which called for women and mothers to seek moments of peace, solitude, and introspection amid the busy realties of modern life.
In addition to her novels and other creative writing, Anne published a significant amount of poetry, including her collection The Unicorn (1956). In 1962 she published the novel Dearly Beloved, concerning the troubles involved in love, relationships, and married life. Later, she published a compendium of essays for Life magazine, issued as Earth Shine. In the 1970s Harcourt Brace publishers, with the help of Anne and Charles, issued volumes containing excerpts from Anne's correspondence and diaries: Bring Me a Unicorn (1971); Hour of Gold, Hour of Lead (1973); Locked Rooms and Open Doors (1974); The Flower and the Nettle (1976); and War Within and Without (1980). Anne lived in Maui with Charles until his death in August 1974 and later moved to Connecticut. Anne Morrow Lindbergh died in 2001.
The Anne Morrow Lindbergh Papers consist of 81 linear feet of material (162 boxes), with the majority of the papers concerning Anne's life and career from the late-1920s to the 1970s.
Organization of the Collection
This collection is organized into six series:
I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS (1917-80, n.d.)
II. DIARIES (1916-58)
III. CORRESPONDENCE (1910-87)
IV. WRITINGS (1935-80)
V. CHARLES LINDBERGH (1912-71)
VI. ADDITIONAL MATERIALS
Abbreviations used in the collection: AML (Anne Morrow Lindbergh); CAL (Charles Augustus Lindbergh), ECM (Elizabeth Cutter Morrow); ELLL (Elizabeth Lodge Land Lindbergh); CCM (Constance Cutter Morgan); and EMM (Elisabeth Morrow Morgan)
The papers are open to researchers according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection.
Anne Morrow Lindbergh's Papers were originally part of the much larger and unprocessed Morrow Family Papers housed in the Sophia Smith Collection, which were first donated to the college in 1955. In her will, Anne stipulated that her papers be restricted until ten years after her death.
Hauptmann, Bruno Richard, 1899-1936-- Kidnapping; Lindbergh, Anne Morrow, 1906-2001; Lindbergh, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), 1902-1974; Lindbergh, Charles Augustus, 1930-1932 -- Kidnapping, 1932; Morgan, Constance Cutter Morrow, 1913-1995; Morgan, Elisabeth Morrow, 1904-1934; Morrow, Elizabeth Reeve Cutter, 1873-1955; Lindbergh family; Morrow family; Europe -- Description and travel -- Sources; Air travel -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Diaries; Family -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Women poets, American -- 20th century; Upper class families -- United States -- History -- Sources; Women authors, American -- 20th century -- Biography -- Sources; Women in aeronautics; Women travelers -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; World War, 1939-1945 -- Personal narratives, American; Lindbergh, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), 1902-1974
Collections related to the Lindberghs and Morrows are housed at the Missouri Historical Society, Yale University, and Amherst College. There is also material related to Anne Morrow Lindbergh, Elizabeth Cutter Morrow, and Constance Morrow Morgan in the Smith College Archives.
Those interested in the life of Anne and Charles Lindbergh should consult Dorothy Hermann, Anne Morrow Lindbergh: A Gift for Life (New York, 1993), A. Scott Berg, Lindbergh (New York, 1998), and Susan Hertog, Anne Morrow Lindbergh: Her Life (New York, 1999).
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS (1917-80, undated)
  This series contains three subseries: General, Newspapers, and Books. The material under the General heading contains papers concerning Anne's years as a high school and college student; her engagement to CAL in 1929; the death of her sister Elisabeth in 1934; the death of her mother and the settling of her mother's estate; and AML's will, financial items, awards and citations, and photographs (including Anne alone, with groups, with CAL, Anne with Morrow family members, and containing photographs from her trip to Asia in 1931). The Newspapers subseries is divided into two sections. The first section consists of thousands of miscellaneous articles and clippings, organized chronologically, focusing on Anne's relationship with CAL, the Morrow and Lindbergh families, and Anne's experiences as an aviator. The second section consists of clippings, 1932-1936, from dozens of state and national newspapers and magazines relating to the kidnapping of Charles Lindbergh, III, and the trial and execution of Bruno Richard Hauptmann. These newspapers, chiefly based in New Jersey and New York, are organized alphabetically by title and then chronologically within each title. The third subseries, Books, contains volumes written about the Lindbergh kidnapping.
- SERIES II. DIARIES (1916-58)
  This series consists of original hand-written volumes and typed carbon copies of transcripts, 1916-1958, penned by Anne Morrow Lindbergh. Some of the diaries, especially those written after 1944, have not been transcribed. Many excerpts from the diaries were included in the five-volume collection of Anne's letters and diaries, beginning with Bring Me a Unicorn and ending with War Within and Without. Some volumes of the diary include correspondence, newspaper clippings, and other items pertaining to AML's life at the time she was writing.
- SERIES III. CORRESPONDENCE (1910-87)
  Correspondence is divided into three subseries: Family, Notable individuals, and Miscellaneous. Family correspondence is organized chronologically according to generation, beginning with Anne's grandfather (Generation 1) and ending with her children (Generation 4). Correspondence includes original and transcribed letters, including significant correspondence between Anne and her mother Elizabeth Cutter Morrow, sister Elisabeth Morrow Morgan, sister Constance Morrow Morgan, mother-in-law Evangeline Lodge Land Lindbergh, and husband Charles A. Lindbergh. The second subseries, Notable individuals, contain AML's letters to Margaret "Monte" Millar, Ruth Oliff Thomas, Sue Beck Vaillant, and Lucia Valentine.
  AML's correspondence also includes several boxes of Miscellaneous letters to friends and associates, which chiefly consist of typescript copies. In instances where only the first name or nickname (i.e., William or Billy, etc.) of a correspondence is given, it is alphabetized as if it were a last name (William under "W," Billy under "B," etc.). Because AML's papers have been used by editors and secretaries over the years for publication, and in some cases letters reside in multiple archives, most of the correspondence in the collection has been transcribed. In the Sophia Smith Collection, there are often either original AML letters with no transcription, or a transcription with no original letter.
- SERIES IV. WRITINGS (1935-80)
  Writings consist of notes, drafts, correspondence, and other materials collected by Anne Morrow Lindbergh, Charles Lindbergh, family members, and editors during the composition of AML's works of fiction, non-fiction, and poetry. Papers in this series are organized chronologically according to the date Anne published a particular work, with the finished, published volume located (when included) at the end of a section concerning a particular work. In each section, the archivist has attempted to organize materials to reflect the creative process from draft to published work-including handwritten notes, typescripts and corrections, galley proofs, and reviews in the order they were created-even when dates for such materials are unknown.
  Materials related to the creation of Anne's works North to the Orient, Gift from the Sea, Dearly Beloved, Earth Shine, and the five volume collection of her letters and diaries are well represented in the collection. Materials Anne compiled for an anthology titled "O to Whom," which she abandoned to write Wave of the Future, are also included.
  Most of the papers concerning publication of North to the Orient were transferred from the Mortimer Rare Book Room at Smith College.
  Material concerning Gift from the Sea includes hundreds of letters from individuals known and unknown to Anne, mostly women and including African Americans, expressing their gratitude for Anne writing the book. These letters include writings by people from around the country, from housewives to authors to Secretary of State George Kennan, who wrote Anne a letter on the inside of the dust jacket of her book, May 1955. Gift from the Sea correspondence also contains letters, often from religious groups, that were critical of the ideas expressed in her book. In some instances, Anne or her secretary made notations (including "*") on incoming correspondence that suggested the letter was "nice," "interesting," "special," or from a "crank." Gift from the Sea letters provide an interesting look at Americans', especially women's, attitudes toward life and work in the 1950s. Letters also include many offers for Anne to speak at colleges, universities, and clubs.
  Correspondence related to The Unicorn includes discussion of the harsh review of Anne's book by poet and critic John Ciardi.
- SERIES V. CHARLES LINDBERGH (1912-71)
  This series is divided into six subseries: Diaries, Correspondence and other papers, Writings, Scrapbooks, Books, and Miscellaneous. Diaries chiefly consist of typed carbon copies of CAL's diaries, though several original volumes are included with an accompanying transcript. Correspondence mostly contains typed carbon copies of letters between CAL and his mother, Evangeline Lodge Land Lindbergh; letters between CAL and Morrow family members; and letters to family secretary and C.F.O. for Morrow properties Arthur Springer. There are also miscellaneous financial items, including matters concerning the Lindberghs' move from America to Europe in 1936. CAL's Writings contain published and unpublished works by Lindbergh and about him. Scrapbooks include hundreds of pages of material collected by Lindbergh enthusiast Willard Morse, in a volume purchased by the Morrow family. Copies of hundreds of items from the New York Times concerning Lindbergh's flight across the Atlantic are also included in the scrapbooks.
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS
  - General
    - Education, 1913-28 (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
    - Engagement and marriage
      - 1929 (Box 1, Folder 6-9)
      - 1929-30 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
    - Death of Elisabeth Morrow Morgan, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Death and estate papers of Elizabeth Cutter Morrow, 1955-63 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Financial items, 1934-70 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Last will and testament of AML; trust agreement, 1980; 1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Citations and awards (Box 2, Folder 8-10)
    - Citations and awards (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Photographs
    - AML alone; silhouettes and portraits of AML; AML with individuals and groups; AML with CAL; AML with members of the Morrow family; and AML with her children, mostly unlabeled (Box 4, Folder 1-10)
    - Photographs of sons Charles Augustus Lindbergh, Jr.; Jon Lindbergh; daughter Anne Lindbergh Feydy; AML's trip to Japan, 1931; miscellaneous photographs kept by AML; negatives; and photocopies (Box 5, Folder 1-7)
  - Miscellaneous newspapers and clippings
    - 1924 - Jul 1931, undated (Box 6, Folder 1-9)
    - Concerning the Lindberghs' trip to Asia, including their efforts to help flood victims in China, Aug 1931 (Box 7, Folder 1-8)
    - Sep 1931 - Apr 1933 (Box 7, Folder 9-15)
    - May - Dec 1933 (Box 8, Folder 1-16)
    - Dec 1933 - Dec 1935 (Box 9, Folder 1-13)
    - Jan 1936 - Mar 1939 (Box 10, Folder 1-17)
    - Apr 1939 - 1942 (Box 11, Folder 1-9)
    - 1943-77, undated(circa 1924-77) (Box 12, Folder 1-8)
  - Newspapers/kidnapping
    - Bergen Evening Record (Newark, N.J.)
      - 1935 - Apr 1936 (Box 12, Folder 9-13)
      - May 1936 - Nov 1937 (Box 13, Folder 1-6)
    - Boston Evening Transcript, 16 Feb 1935 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Brooklyn Daily Eagle, Mar 1932 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Congressional Record, concerning legislation passed in the wake of the Lindbergh kidnapping case 6 Jan 1936 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Englewood Press, 1932, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Hearst's International Cosmopolitan, May 1935 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Hudson Dispatch, Mar-Apr 1932 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Liberty, 1935-36 (Box 13, Folder 13-15)
    - The Literary Digest, 1935-36 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Newark Evening News
      - 1932 - Jul 1936 (Box 13, Folder 17-23)
      - Aug 1936 - Dec 1937 (Box 14, Folder 1-4)
    - Newark Sunday Call (selections)1935-36 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Newsweek(selections) 1935-36 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - New York American, Mar 1932 - 1937 (Box 15, Folder 7-16)
    - New York Daily Mirror
      - Mar 1932 - Dec 1935 (Box 15, Folder 1-13)
      - Jan 1936 - 1937 (Box 16, Folder 1-7)
    - New York Daily News
      - Mar 1932 - Oct 1934 (Box 16, Folder 8-13)
      - Jan 1935 - Apr 1936 (Box 17, Folder 1-9)
      - May 1936 - 1937 (Box 18, Folder 1-3)
    - New York Evening Graphic, 1932 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - New York Herald Tribune
      - Mar 1932 - Oct 1934 (Box 18, Folder 5-11)
      - Nov 1934 - 1937 (Box 19, Folder 1-11)
    - New York Journal
      - Mar 1932 - Jan 1935 (Box 20, Folder 1-9)
      - Feb 1935 - Apr 1936 (Box 21, Folder 1-8)
      - May 1936 - 1937 (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
    - New York Law Journal (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - New York Post, May 1932 - Dec 1936 (Box 22, Folder 4-12)
    - New York Sun
      - Mar 1932 - 10 Jan 1935 (Box 22, Folder 13-16)
    - New York Times
      - 11 Jan 1935 - Dec 1937 (Box 23, Folder 1-13)
      - Mar 1932 - Jan 1935 (Box 24, Folder 1-13)
      - Feb 1935 - 1937 (Box 24, Folder 1-10)
    - New York World Telegram
      - 1932 - Sep 1934 (Box 25, Folder 11-13)
      - Oct 1934 - 1937 (Box 26, Folder 1-10)
    - The New Yorker (selections) 1935 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Philadelphia Enquirer, 9 Mar 1932 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Providence Evening Bulletin, Mar 1932 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Providence Journal, 1932 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Radio Guide, Mar - Apr 1936 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Time (selections), 1936 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Trenton Evening Times, 3 Mar 1932 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Voice of Experience, Apr 1936 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Warsaw Weekly, 21 Feb 1935 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Unknown newspapers (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Kidnapping miscellany, including "Jafsie Notes," containing newspaper clippings of the ransom notes exchanged between Dr. John F. "Jafsie" Condon and the Lindbergh baby's kidnapper, and "The Lindbergh Kidnapping Case," compiled by Ruth T. Robertson (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Books
    - The Great Lindbergh Hullabaloo (1932) by Laura Vitray (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - True Story of the Lindbergh Kidnapping by John Brant and Edith Renaud1932 (Box 27, Folder 11)
- SERIES II. DIARIES
  - Original
    - The Kidnapping Business by Edward Dean Sullivan1932
    - The Lindbergh Crime by Sidney B. Whipple 1935 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - (including loose handwritten pages)1916-19 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - 1920-21 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - 1922-24 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - (concerning AML's summer abroad) 1926 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - (including original correspondence)1927-28 (Box 29, Folder 3-4)
    - 1932 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - 1933 - Mar 1936 (Box 30, Folder 1-4)
    - Apr - Nov 1936 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Christmas 1936, including correspondence with friends and family (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - 31 Jan 1937 - 30 Sep 1938 (Box 31, Folder 3-4)
    - 11 Nov 1938 - 25 Oct 1941 (Box 32, Folder 1-5)
    - 18 Jul 1942 - 7 Dec 1956 (Box 33, Folder 1-5)
    - 4 Jan 1957 - 3 May 1959 (Box 34, Folder 1-3)
    - 4 May 1959 - Dec 1959 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Undated diary, "Strictly Private!", including small address book (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Undated diary, "Supplemental Diary" (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Diary transcriptions: carbon copies
    - 1919 - Aug 1924 (Box 35, Folder 4-8)
    - 1926 - Jan 1935 (Box 36, Folder 1-7)
    - Jan 1935 - Jul 1938 (Box 37, Folder 1-5)
    - 11 Jul 1938 - 16 Jun 1940 (Box 38, Folder 1-7)
    - 16 Jun 1940 - 20 Jan 1944 (Box 39, Folder 1-8)
    - 16 Jan 1944 - 1947 (Box 40, Folder 1-4)
- SERIES III. CORRESPONDENCE
  - Generation 1
    - Charles Cutter (b. 1842) 1914 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Annie Elizabeth Cutter (b. 1845): correspondence and carbon copies 1913-37, undated (Box 40, Folder 6-11)
  - Generation 2
    - Annie Cutter: correspondence and carbon copies 1913-45 (Box 40, Folder 12-14)
    - Edith Cutter Yates 1916-37, undated (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Agnes Morrow Scandett (b. 1869) circa 1940-43 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Jay Johnson Morrow (b. 1870) 1937, undated (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Alice Morrow (1871-1932) 1922, undated (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Dwight Morrow (1873-1931) and carbon copies 1907-27, undated (Box 41, Folder 5-6)
    - Hilda Morrow McIlvaine (b. 1874) 1938, 1940 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Elizabeth Cutter Morrow (1873-1955)
      - 1910-27, undated (Box 41, Folder 8-14)
      - 1928 - Aug 1931 (Box 42, Folder 1-6)
      - Sep 1931 - 1935 (Box 43, Folder 1-7)
      - 1936 - May 1938 (Box 44, Folder 1-5)
      - Jul 1938 - 1943, undated (Box 45, Folder 1-8)
      - 1944-54, undated (Box 46, Folder 1-9)
      - Carbon copies, 1915-29 (Box 46, Folder 10-12)
      - Carbon copies, 1930-37 (Box 47, Folder 1-5)
      - Carbon copies, 1938-1954, undated (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Evangeline Lodge Land Lindbergh (1876-1954)
      - 1928 - May 1932 (Box 49, Folder 1-9)
      - Jun 1932 - 1937 (Box 50, Folder 1-8)
      - 1938 - Dec 1945 (Box 51, Folder 1-10)
      - 1946-49, undated (Box 52, Folder 1-3)
      - Carbon copies, 1928-1937 (Box 52, Folder 4-7)
      - Carbon copies, 1938-47, undated (Box 53, Folder 1-4)
  - Generation 3
    - Elisabeth Morrow Morgan (1904-34)
      - 1919-22 (Box 53, Folder 5-6)
      - undated(circa 1919-1922) (Box 54, Folder 1-9)
      - Jan 1933 - 1934, undated (Box 55, Folder 1-7)
      - Carbon copies, 1920-33 (Box 55, Folder 8)
      - Carbon copies, 1920-33 (Box 56, Folder 1-3)
    - Constance Morrow Morgan (1913-95)
      - 1925-36, [see also, box 158, folders 3-7] (Box 56, Folder 4-9)
      - 1937-62, [see also, box 158, folders 8-11 and boxes 159-161] (Box 57, Folder 1-12)
      - 1963-87, undated (Box 58, Folder 1-7)
      - Carbon copies (Box 58, Folder 8-17)
    - Aubrey Morgan (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Dwight Morrow, Jr. (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Margot Loines Morrow
      - 1938-47 (Box 59, Folder 5-7)
      - Carbon copies (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Charles A. Lindbergh
      - 1928 - 9 May 1942 (Box 59, Folder 9-12)
      - 16 May 1942 - Dec 1947 (Box 60, Folder 1-9)
      - 1950-51, undated (Box 61, Folder 1)
      - Carbon copies, 1928-50 (Box 61, Folder 2-5)
  - Generation 4
    - Jon Lindbergh 1934-47 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Anne Lindbergh Feydy circa 1945-47, 1987, undated (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Scott Lindbergh 1945-50, undated (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Land Lindbergh 1945-47, 1977, 1980, undated (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - Reeve Lindbergh Brown 1947, 1977 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Reeve Lindbergh Brown, "Under a Wing" 1998 (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Notable individuals
    - Margaret Bartlett "Monte" Millar
      - 1935 - Jan 1936 (Box 61, Folder 11-12)
      - Feb 1936-45 (Box 62, Folder 1-3)
      - Carbon copies (Box 62, Folder 4-5)
    - Ruth Oliff Thomas
      - 1939-44 (Box 62, Folder 6-9)
      - 1945-69, undated (Box 63, Folder 1-7)
      - Carbon copies (Box 63, Folder 8-9)
    - Suzanna Beck Vaillant
      - 1929-41 (Box 63, Folder 10)
      - 1942-47, undated (Box 64, Folder 1-5)
      - Carbon copies (Box 64, Folder 6-7)
    - Lucia Norton Valentine 1927-87, undated (Box 65, Folder 1-8)
  - Miscellaneous
    - A - C (Box 66, Folder 1-7)
    - D - Delafield (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - De Latte - Lee, Thelma Crawford (Box 67, Folder 1-9)
    - Miscellaneous, Lehmann - R (Box 68, Folder 1-8)
    - Miscellaneous, S - Z (Box 69, Folder 1-6)
    - Unidentified (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - Typed carbon copies
    - 1907-1942, including letters to friends and family members from previous sections 1907-1942 (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - 1930-39 (Box 70, Folder 1-9)
    - 1940-43 (Box 71, Folder 1-9)
    - 1943-48 (Box 72, Folder 1-8)
- SERIES IV. WRITINGS
  - North to the Orient
    - Original folder, containing brief letter from CAL (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Handwritten notes and drafts (Box 73, Folder 2-8)
    - Flight logs, handwritten notes and drafts (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Corrected typescripts, pt. 1Feb - Apr 1934 (Box 73, Folder 10)